# PRAKASH VINCENT LEELA

prakashkkml@gmail.com · +61-410 010 834 | 1 Sandhurst Cres, Upper Coomera - 4209, Gold Coast, QLD <a href="https://prakashvl.page">https://prakashvl.page</a> · <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/prakashvl">https://www.linkedin.com/in/prakashvl</a> ·

https://stackoverflow.com/users/5675572 · https://www.hackerrank.com/4LPH4 · user0505PF - LeetCode Profile

- Overall, 7+ years of experience in Information Technology industry in various roles with expertise in Design, Analysis, Coding, Testing and Documentation on full-stack versatile frameworks.
- Having 3+ years of overseas work experience from Germany.
- Java and JavaScript Developer with exclusive experience in Micro-services architecture.
- Hold cutting edge technologies experience on RMQ, Kafka, Docker, k8s, Micro Service, Java 17 and Typescript.
- Security implications for web applications (OWASP)

#### WORK AUTHORIZATION

**HOLDING AUSTRALIA'S WORK RIGHTS** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

MAR 2023 - MAR 2024

## **EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER,** REDCARE PHARMACY (formerly SHOP APOTHEKE EUROPE)

Project: E-Commerce Online Pharmacy (We aim to help our customers live healthily)

- Keeping customers in the center. Seek to deliver measurable customer value by following a hypothesis driven development approach.
- Creating and consuming micro-service RESTful APIs and events, that operate at scale, serving 10M+ customers across Europe.
- Part of the promotion team and created an e-commerce promotion engine from scratch, capable to serve millions of promotions to different countries.
- Securing service APIs with authentication mechanisms (Basic AUTH, OAuth and JWT)
- o Tech stack is Java, NodeJS, Spring Boot, RMQ, MongoDB, MySQL, Kubernetes, Google Cloud.

#### **DEC 2020 - FEB 2023**

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER, M.DOC GMBH SMART HEALTH EVOLUTION

Project: Smart Health Platform (WebApp, Micro-services, IOS App, Android App)

- Participate in the process of requirement collection, discussion for shaping the functional requirements, and developing the health care software with high availability and performance.
- End-to-end platform development and maintenance with Spring-boot Rest and Stream API microservices backend, Angular for frontend, RabbitMQ, Keycloak, Mongo-DB (nosql) and PostgreSQL(sql) for persistence.
- Designed and implemented Inter-Operability (HL7 and FHIR integration support) for the m.Doc healthcare platform via MIRTH (JavaScript programming).
- o Conducted Scrum meetings and guide teams to solve their technical problems with the best fit technologies and appropriate design patterns.
- o Improved code quality with code reviews, unit, and integration tests.
- Maintaining proper documentation for the product.

**SEPT 2018 - OCT 2020** 

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER, QUEST GLOBAL SERVICES PVT LTD** 

Project: Clinical Care Solutions (CCS) Viewer and KYMA platform (GE Healthcare)

- End to end development using Java and JavaScript micro-services architecture.
- Develop and deploy Stream and Rest API micro-Services using Spring-boot, Kafka, Docker, Java, Kubernetes and helm umbrella chart.
- Understanding integration scenarios, develop an Angular/redux/Typescript structure as per the UI specifications, and the client given product requirements.
- o Writing end to end unit test and behavior-driven development (BDD) using selenium.
- Used chrome networking tools, curl and postman, Prometheus Grafana and Kibana for performance monitoring and log debugging, and chrome developer tools to debug the JavaScript files.
- o Performing design, coding, code review, and code estimations.
- o Grooming tickets, understanding requirements, client discussion and managing standups.
- Maintaining proper documentation for the product.

## **SEPT 2016 - AUG 2018**

#### **SENIOR ASSOCIATE II, NTTDATA (formerly DELL INTERNATIONAL SERVICES)**

Project: VB6 Elimination Project (Jackson National Life Insurance)

- Developed Full stack application using JEE 7 architecture, using Prime faces, JSF, XHTML to design the user interfaces, CDI/EJB Spring for middleware services and JPA/Hibernate for database interaction.
- o Developed GUI using CSS, HTML/HTML5, and JQuery.
- o Implemented continuous delivery and maintenance using Atlassian suite (Jira, Bamboo, stash)
- Analyzing existing VB6 code, ensuring design in a multi-tenant environment, so that introduction on new functionality does not hamper old builds.
- o Estimating time-frame for the requirement and analyzing effort for the functionality.
- Designing low-level UML diagrams to the code APIs estimated.
- o Performed Development, Bug fixing, extensively involved in regression testing and Help document creation so the users can easily understand.

#### **EDUCATION**

**APRIL 2015 (FIRST CLASS)** 

**B.E COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING,** ANNA UNIVERSITY CHENNAI – INDIA

**APRIL 2012 (FIRST CLASS WITH DISTINCTION)** 

**DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, DOTE TAMILNADU – INDIA** 

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java Stack

• Java 17, Spring-boot 3.2, Spring-MVC, JSF2, Servlet 3.0, JSP, JPA/Hibernate, JVisual-VM, JConsole.

JavaScript Stack

• JavaScript, Angular 8, Redux, NPM, JQuery, node-JS

Version Control • GitHub, GitLab, SourceTree, Bitbucket

Message broker • RabbitMQ, Kafka

Database
 MySQL, IBM DB2, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

IDEs • VS Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA

Log management tool • Telemetry Elastic, Kibana

Build tools • Maven, Yarn, NPM, Docker

Deployment tool • Jenkins, Helm chart

Server tools • Undertow, Tomcat, JBoss 7.1

UML Tool • Miro, MS Visio

Project/Defect Tracking • Jira, Rally

Methodologies • Agile, Waterfall

Code Generator • OpenAPI (Previously known as Swagger)

## ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Completed RabbitMQ certification from CloudAMQP
- On the fly and Rising star awards from QUEST GLOBAL
- On the spot award from NTTDATA
- Completed Embedded System Design online certification from IIT Kharagpur (Conducted by NPTEL Govt. of India)
- Paper presented (2PVC Two-Phase Validation and Commit Protocol) in National conference conducted by Hindustan Institute of Technology Coimbatore.
- Rotaract club volunteer at Udaya School of Engineering (Jun 2013 Apr 2014)

## PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

- Amal G M, Staff Software Architect,
  - o Email: gmamal@gmail.com
  - o GE Healthcare Banglore India (LinkedIn)
- Vipindas Marydasan, Solution Architect,
  - o Email: vipinwww@gmail.com
  - Ströer SE & Co. KGaA Cologne Germany (LinkedIn)